http://www.bw.edu/privacy/index

Give
Search:
Basketball Locker Room Renovation
Thank you!
Center for Innovation & Growth
Digital Marketing Clinic (DMC)
Video
BW Builds Northeast Ohio's "Brain Gain"
Privacy Statement
Baldwin Wallace University (BW) is committed to protecting the privacy of website visitors as well as the privacy of our students, parents, legal guardians, faculty, staff, alumni and friends. This privacy statement describes the type of information that may be collected from visitors to BW's websites and is updated as necessary to reflect current collection methods and usage of website visitor information.Information SharingBW does not sell or rent website visitor information and does not share website visitor information except as compelled by law.BW also complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which prohibits the release of education records except in limited circumstances (i.e., with the student's permission, to parents of dependent students and in response to a valid court order). Although FERPA regulations apply only to students, BW is equally committed to protecting the privacy of all visitors to its websites. BW also complies with the applicable provisions of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA) and the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).What information is collected?Anonymous InformationBW may collect and store website visitor information such as referrer pages, date/time stamps, pages requested, browser and computer information, user agent, headers, files downloaded and any errors encountered.Personal InformationBaldwin Wallace acknowledges that there are many potential definitions of “personal information.” BW defines personal information as any information about an identified or identifiable person. This can include direct identifiers (e.g., name, address, email address or national identification numbers) or indirect identifiers (e.g., location data or IP address). This list of data elements is not exhaustive, and BW considers the definition of personal data in the broadest possible context.How Is Information Collected?BW may use a variety of methods including, but not limited to, network, server and browser technologies to collect website visitor information. Some examples:CookiesScriptsServer logsCustom URL parametersTracking imagesInformation and correspondence submitted voluntarily by website visitors via forms, comments, chats, etcPhone advertising IDWhy Is Information Collected?BW collects website visitor information to best serve audiences by optimizing and personalizing visitor experiences in both digital and physical spaces, to manage visitor relationships with the University, to foster/promote further communications, to gauge communication effectiveness, to gain insights into user behavior and preferences, to track interests, to identify errors and issues, recruitment, and to conduct market research.Is Collected Information Secure?The security of all data is very important to BW. For data collected from website visitors, BW follows the guidance prescribed in the University's IT policies.How Long Is Information Stored?BW only retains personal data for the duration necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. Personal data may also be retained for longer periods if it is solely for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes, or statistical purposes. When defining the appropriate retention length, BW adheres to relevant legal requirements, such as regulations and basic requirements listed in HIPAA, FERPA or other state or federal regulations.Third PartiesBW may contract or partner with external third parties to place ads on BW websites not affiliated with the University. These non-affiliated sites may send and share visitor information and browsing behavior, collected in accordance with their own privacy policies, with BW. These third-party websites may also display advertisements to previous visitors of a BW website. Children/MinorsBW does not knowingly collect website visitor information from children or minors as defined by the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). The Federal Trade Commission provides guides for protecting the privacy of children visiting websites at https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/topics/protecting-kids-online.Opting OutBW respects the privacy decisions of its constituents. Website visitors may choose not to have data collected by BW websites through a variety of ways:Most modern web browsers provide a user privacy setting. When enabled, the browser tells websites to disable their information collection methods. For more information, visit https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Do_Not_Track.Responsible internet advertisers have tools to opt-out or control advertisements and tracking, such as: http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/https://choice.microsoft.com/https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=enhttps://www.facebook.com/help/769828729705201/QuestionsPlease email info@bw.edu with any questions about this privacy statement.
Placeholder
Menu
CALLING ALL SEEKERS, LEADERS, OVERACHIEVERS AND DREAMERS
EXPLORE BW
APPLY NOW
VISIT CAMPUS
Facebook Twitter YouTube Instagram Flickr Linkedin
More Information
Undergraduate AdmissionFirst-Year StudentsConservatory StudentsTransfer StudentsAdult StudentsReturning/Former StudentsGuest StudentsVeteran StudentsInternational StudentsStudent LifeStudent LifeHousingDiningClubs & OrganizationsTraditionsStudent ServicesService & LeadershipSports & RecreationWellnessArts & Culture
Graduate & Professional AdmissionMaster of Business AdministrationMaster of AccountancyMaster of Arts in EducationSuperintendent's LicenseTeacher License + Master'sInitial Teacher LicensureLeadership in Higher EducationSchool Social WorkPhysician AssistantSpeech-Language PathologyMaster of Public HealthNursingMusic Therapy Equivalency Certification
Tuition & Financial AidTuition & FeesFinancial AidBilling & PaymentsTrendingAcademic CalendarBach FestivalBookstoreBW at Corporate College EastCenter for Innovation & GrowthConference ServicesConservatory of MusicLibrariesNew Student OrientationTranscripts
AboutAbout BWLocationDiversityLeadershipHistoryAthletics Varsity Yellow JacketsIntramural & Club SportsResources for:Student Consumer InformationParents & FamilyAlumniCommunity
AcademicsOverviewUndergraduate ProgramsGraduate & Professional ProgramsEvening ProgramsOnline ProgramsProfessional DevelopmentResearchStudy AbroadStudent SuccessCollege to CareerCourse CatalogRegistration & Records
Baldwin Wallace University  |  275 Eastland Rd. Berea, Ohio 44017  |  (440) 826-2900  |  info@bw.eduContact Us | Privacy | Employment & Careers | Emergency InformationJump to Top of Page
Admission
Undergraduate Admission
Academics
Student Life
Graduate & Professional Programs
Athletics
About
News & Events
BW Builds Northeast Ohio's "Brain Gain"
2015 Holiday Card
Privacy Statement
BW Impacts Northeast Ohio
VIRTUAL ADMISSION COUNSELOR APPOINTMENTSMyBWDIRECTORYCAMPUS MAPCOMMUNITYPARENTS & FAMILYALUMNIGIVEFALL 2020 UPDATES
